

Location:	Saint-Petersburg, Russia
E-mail:	mgrigoriev@gmail.com
Phone:	+7 (931) 227-83-84 (WhatsApp, Telegram)
GitHub:	https://github.com/mgrigoriev

#### **SUMMARY**

Seasoned Ruby on Rails developer with experience in a wide range of technologies and projects (e-commerce, education, telecom, CRM, etc.). I pay great attention to writing clean and maintainable code, automated testing, effective written communication, and deep understanding of a business domain.

#### **SKILLS**

- Ruby on Rails (5+ years)
- TDD/BDD (RSpec, Capybara)
- PostgreSQL
- Sidekiq
- REST API
- Payment system integration: Stripe, MandarinBank
- Mandrill API
- HAML, SASS, Bootstrap; JavaScript, jQuery, CoffeeScript
- Deployment (Capistrano)
- Linux, Nginx, Passenger
- Circle CI, Airbrake, Datadog
- Debugging and performance optimization

### **OTHER SKILLS**

Requirements gathering, UX prototyping, clear written communication.

# **EXPERIENCE**

### SHOW-SCORE, New York (remote)

Ruby on Rails Developer, April 2018 — March 2020

Show-Score is a community of people who enjoy theater.

I had been working on backend and full-stack implementation of new features/tools for members and admin team, refactoring, performance optimization, increasing of test coverage, email marketing related tasks. Implemented internal currency system, geo location services, created API services.

Tech stack: Ruby on Rails 5, PostgreSQL, RSpec, Sidekiq, Mandrill API, Stripe, CoffeeScript, React.

# AIRSTRIPE, Madrid (remote)

Ruby on Rails Developer, October 2017 — January 2018

Airstripe is a flight reservation startup. I created the site from scratch, including booking system, integration with Stripe, internationalization, and admin tools. Tech stack: Ruby on Rails 5, Postgres, Sidekiq, RSpec, Bootstrap.

### **THINKNETICA, Moscow (remote)**

**Ruby on Rails Developer**, February — October 2017

Implemented a CRM system for the popular Ruby programming school. Created modules for invoicing, managing courses, groups and students. Implemented payment system integration (MandarinBank). Built automated tests at all levels.

### **GOSSTANDART EXPERT**

Ruby on Rails Developer and co-founder, January 2013 — April 2018

Created a CRM/ERP solution for managing business processes of the company.

Tech stack: Ruby on Rails 4/5, RSpec, Capybara, Bootstrap, jQuery.

#### **USABILITYLAB**

Project manager at UX agency, 2012 - 2013

Ran a lot of projects related to user experience research, design, usability testing, and eye-tracking.

#### **KAVANGA!**

**UX designer,** 2009 - 2012

Designed user interfaces for a digital advertising platform. Gained a lot of experience in requirements gathering, understanding of software development lifecycle.

### **OPENTODO**

Author of open-source project, 2008 - 2009

Created an open-source task management application. Tech stack: Python / Django.

#### **KOLATELECOM**

Lead software developer, 2006 — 2009

Built intranet system for business processes automation; control panel for ISP subscribers; e-commerce portal with the ability to buy movies and music. Implemented modern software development practices: version control, staging server. Tech stack: Python / Django, Perl, PHP, MySQL, Oracle.

### **ARCTIC MEDIA GROUP**

Web-developer, 2005 - 2006

Created websites for clients of the digital agency. Tech stack: PHP, MySQL, JavaScript.

### **NETSL**

**Web-developer**, 2003 — 2004

Built bug-tracking system, intranet modules, and websites, including e-commerce projects.

# **CODE EXAMPLES**

# Big Business, starter CRM/ERP app

GitHub: https://github.com/mgrigoriev/big business

### **EDUCATION**

Murmansk State Technical University (2000 - 2005): Management, specialist degree Additional trainings:

- Thinknetica (2016): Ruby on Rails professional development, advanced level.
- Thinknetica (2019): DevOps for developers (Docker, Ansible, Vagrant).